我们必须告诉他
We have to tell him.
希望他没事
I hope he's okay.
沃特 我们隔壁的老邻居 过世了
Walt, our elderly next door neighbor, died.
他和卢克非常亲近
He and Luke were pretty close,
所以我们必须得告诉他
so we have to tell him.
我对此有点小紧张
I'm a little nervous about it.
我想我们应该循序渐进地告诉他
I think we should break it to him slowly.
比如
Like how?
第一天我们就说
Well, first we'd say,
卢克 你的朋友沃特得了感冒
"Luke, your friend Walt has a cold.
你就别去他家了
You shouldn't go over there."
第二天就说 不好了 沃特进了医院
Next day--"Bad news. Walt's in the hospital,
不过他还能和护士们谈笑风生
but he's still cracking jokes with the nurses."
第三天 他们正尝试使用
Next day--"They're trying
一种尚在试验阶段的新药
an experimental drug.
但愿他没事
Fingers crossed."
第四天 他产生了排斥反应
Next day--"His body rebelled.
陷入了昏迷
He's in a coma."
第五天 他醒了 第六天 又昏了
Next day--he rallies, next day--coma,
第七天 仍然昏
Next day--coma,
第八天 继续昏
next day--coma,
第九天 眼皮轻颤
next day--eye flutter--
打住 打住 别说了
Stop. Just stop. Stop.
卢克 我们不得不告诉你一个坏消息
Oh, Luke, we have some bad news for you.
是有关沃特的
It's about Walt.
很抱歉
I'm afraid...
他去世了
He passed away.
是昨天的事
Um, it happened yesterday.
他刚给邮政部长写完了一封
He finished writing an angry letter
满怀怒气的信 然后就睡死过去了
to the postmaster general, and he just fell asleep.
好吧
Okay.
一切都很很平静
It was very peaceful.
除了那信 信里全是威胁恐吓 不过
Not the letter. That was full of threats, but...
你伤心也是应该的 宝贝
It's okay to be sad, honey.
你们俩是非常好的朋友
You two were really good friends.
听到这消息你一定很震惊吧
It must be quite a shock to hear that...
沃特他死了
Walt's dead.
你想和我们谈谈心吗
Um, so do you wanna talk about it or...
我没事
I'm okay.
我能回去玩游戏了吗 我按了暂停
Can I get back to my video game? It's paused.
没问题
Oh, um, sure.
老弟
Yeah, buddy.
过来抱抱
Come here.
他的表现也太奇怪了
How weird was that?
我知道 太诡异了
I know. Crazy weird.
他简直就像是铁石心肠一样
It's like he had no feelings at all.
我倒觉得你的表现比较诡异
I'm more worried about the one you showed.
你那微笑是什么意思
What's with all the smiling?
你在说什么啊
What are you talking about?
你那咧嘴一笑
That grin.
"沃特他死了" 跟蝙蝠侠里小丑似的
"Walt's dead." You looked like the Joker.
我才没笑呢
I didn't smile.
你笑了 就像是某种怪异的应对机制
You did. It's like a weird coping mechanism.
上次你告诉他仓鼠死时也是这幅摸样
You did the same thing when you told him his hamster died.
我不知道你以为自己看见了什么 菲尔
I don't know what you thought you saw, Phil,
可我们的儿子刚刚听到了悲惨的消息
but our child just got some terrible news
却表现得平静异常 你对此不担心吗
and had absolutely no reaction. Doesn't that concern you?
当然担心 他只是需要时间来消化而已
Yeah. He probably just needs time to process it.
你这么想吗
Do you think?
是啊 亲爱的
Yeah, honey.
生死离别对任何年纪的人都很难面对
Death is a profound thing to deal with at any age.
我们的处理方式各不相同
We all manage it differently.
有的人隐藏他们的感受
Some people lock up their feelings.
其他人则
Others...
转向他人寻求慰藉
reach out for comfort,
设法再次确认自己那鲜活的肉体...
finding some way to reaffirm their connection to life--
想都别想
You're joking.
你好啊 海莉
Hola, Haley.
歌洛莉亚 我开车经过
Gloria, I was driving by
看到门外放了报纸 就给你送进来了
and saw this outside your door, so here.
-谢了 -不客气
- Thank you. - No problem.
既然我人都来了
Hey, so since I'm already here,
我朋友今晚本来要开一个泳池派对
my friend was gonna have a pool party tonight,
可他生病了 能让我们在这里开吗
but he got sick. Could we have it here?
幸好你看到报纸了
Mm. Good thing that you saw this paper
不然你永远没机会开口问了
or if not, you would have never been able to ask.
说得是啊
Yeah.
抱歉 我和杰今晚
I'm sorry, but Jay and I are going
要去米奇和小卡家吃晚饭呢
to Mitch and Cam's for dinner tonight.
你就当我自言自语好了
I'm just thinking out loud here.
如果有个我父母同意的监护人全程陪同
What if I get a chaperone that my parents approve of?
你会答应吗
Would it be okay then?
这样的话 行啊
Well, I guess so.
说起来 如果曼尼也能放松一下也不错
You know, it would be good for Manny to have a little bit of fun.
你介意他留下来参加派对吗
Do you mind if he stays here for the party?
介意 整个计划都指望他了
Mind? The plan depended on him.
你大概没考虑过监护人的问题吧
I don't suppose you've thought of a chaperone?
当然没想过 妈妈
Of course not, mom,
因为我的派对将会狂野放荡
because it's going to be a wild party
而我也会和往常一样想要逃脱惩罚
and I'm trying to get away with something, as usual.
我当然考虑过监护人的事
Yes, I thought of a chaperone--
舅舅已经答应做我的监护人了
My uncle who already said he would do it.
如果那样还不行的话
But if that's gonna be a problem,
-我就只好打电话通知各位 -抱歉
- I think I should just call everybody-- - sorry.
我错了 我批准了
Sorry. Sorry. It's fine.
谢谢您啦 曼尼舅舅
And thank you, uncle Manny.
你能不能搭把手啊
Can you help a little bit?
如果我按下这里 就会
This--if I--if I push down, does that...
好一点了 好一点了
Yeah, that's helping. That's helping.
不 一点都不好 都卡住了
No, it's not helping. It's 'cause it's stuck.
真不敢相信我居然把它卡住了
I can't believe I got 'em this stuck.
我这辈子都在造床
I've built beds my whole life--
双层床 狗狗的床 牛牛的床
Bunk beds, dog beds, cow beds.
我打赌你绝对没造过牛牛的床
Okay, I'm calling you on cow beds.
我爸来了
Oh, that's my dad!
太好了 他能帮上忙
Okay. He can help.
他造过船 码头 湖泊
He's built a boat, a dock, a lake...
他绝对没造过湖泊
Uh, he did not build a lake.
从今往后 举例时编到第二个就打住吧
Okay, from now on, just stop after you say the second thing.
驾驶舱门打开了
...So the cabin door swings open.
飞行员居然是个女的
Damned if there wasn't a lady pilot in there.
你说得对
Yeah, well,
我不愿意承认 可是我对此也很不爽
I hate to admit it, but it throws me, too.
我还是喜欢男人一点
I do prefer a man.
我们又得就你的取向讨论一番吗
Are we gonna have this conversation again?
-莫尔 -你好吗
- Hey, Merle. - Hey. How are you?
-好吧 -很高兴见到你
- Yeah, ooh. Okay. - Nice to see you.
让我帮你提这个吧
All right, let me grab that for you.
不 我自己来就好
No. No. I got it.
你如果愿意帮我拿瓶啤酒 那可敢情好
I will take that beer you were about to offer me, though.
啤酒马上就来
Oh, yeah. Coming right up.
你知道东西都在哪儿 快坐下吧
And you know where everything is. Go have a seat.
有个我爸的未接来电呢
Oh, I missed a call from my dad.
让我猜猜 是打来取消晚餐的吧
Oh, let me guess. Is he calling to cancel?
这次又是什么借口
What's his excuse this time?
你这么想真是小肚鸡肠 小卡
You know, that's a really mean thing to assume, Cam.
你可以不要总是揪着我爸不放吗
I really wish you'd give my dad a break for once.
得了吧 你明知道杰不待见我爸
Oh, please. You know Jay doesn't like my dad.
他觉得我爸是乡下来的土包子
He thinks he's some bumpkin from the sticks.
我会让你们知道莫尔·斯通沃尔·塔克
Well, I will have you know that Merle Stonewall Tucker
可是全密苏里州最牛逼
is one of the most respected farmers
最受人尊敬的农民
in all of hell's hollow, Missouri.
你也不听听你自己说的话
Okay, you're not hearing yourself.
我爸并不讨厌你爸 别这样
My dad likes him just fine. Come on.
喂 老爸 是我
Hello? Hey, dad. It's me.
米奇
Mitch.
我病了
I'm sick.
我今晚来不了了
I gotta cancel tonight.
没错没错 6点 期待你们的光临
Yeah. Yeah, 6:00. We're really looking forward to it.
你什么意思 我不是说不能来了吗
What are you doing? I just said I can't come.
我不知道 等我问一下
I don't know. Let me ask.
我爸问是喝红酒还是白酒
My dad wants to know red or white?
红酒吧
Um, uh, red.
红酒吧 是我错了
Red. And I'm sorry.
没事 小卡让带红酒
Okay. Yeah, Cam says red.
是的 对 他挺开心的
Okay. Yeah, he's--he's so happy--
省省吧 老家伙 我知道你没病
Knock it off, old man. You are not sick.
为什么你总是这样
Why do you always do this?
听着 咱自家人私底下说
Okay, look, between you and me,
我觉得莫维斯人挺烦的
Mervis kind of bugs me.
首先 人家叫莫尔
Okay, first of all, it's Merle.
莫维斯都不是个名字 只是种声音
Mervis isn't a name. Mervis is a sound.
其次 他可是我爱人的爸爸啊
And second of all, he's-- he's my partner's father.
懂没 你必须得来
Okay? You're coming.
老爸 你干嘛不四处转转
Okay, dad, why don't you settle in?
杰跟歌洛莉亚来就餐之前 我们没什么安排
We don't have plans until dinner tonight with Jay and Gloria.
我不喜欢那家伙
I-I don't like that guy.
什么 这...
What? That's--
你不对谁都挺好的嘛
You like everybody.
除了杰 他有时候让我觉得很烦
Not Jay. The guy rubs me the wrong way.
每次我一想 表达我的善意时
Every time I try to do something nice,
他都给我摆一张臭脸 就像这样
he makes this cranky face, like...
行了 这样吧
Okay. Well, you know what?
我就当你是时差还没到过来
I'm gonna chalk this up to jet lag
因为这一点都不像你
for you because it's not like you at all.
你得稍微试着接纳他
Okay, you have to make an effort.
他可是我爱人的父亲
It's my partner's father.
咆哮一下给我听 就当你同意了
Now give me the growl that means "Okay."
很好
Good.
你知道沃特有个女儿
Did you know Walt had a daughter
却和他形同陌路吗
he was completely estranged from?
律师说他女儿甚至不愿了却他的遗愿
His lawyer said she wouldn't even honor his last request
不肯把他的狗牌扔进大海
to toss his dog tags in the ocean.
真是难以置信
Can you imagine?
菲尔 真的有必要再谈这茬吗
Phil, do we really have to go through this again?
我答应过你 我肯定会尽全力
I told you, I would do everything possible
保证把你的骸骨
to make sure that your skeleton
贡献给女子大学做科学课堂教材
ends up in a science class at a women's college.
不是 只是有些伤感
No, it's just sad.
我晚年生活的一半就指着
That's half of what would keep me going in my old age--
回忆跟孩子们的幸福时光过活了
remembering all the good times with the kids.
教卢克骑自行车
Teaching Luke to ride his bike...
跟海莉跳父女舞
Haley at the father-daughter dance...
第一次带艾丽克斯骑小马
Taking Alex for her first pony ride...
你从没带她骑过小马
You never took Alex on a pony ride.
哦对 就我一人去的
Oh, right. That was just me.
但我带艾丽克斯去了...
But Alex and I went...
不对 那次是带海莉去的
Oh, no. That was Haley.
菲尔 你看 是卢克
Phil, look. It's Luke.
他要进沃特家了
He's going into Walt's house.
他这是要去告别一下
Oh, he's saying good-bye.
说了他只是需要点时间
He just needed a little time.
真是又感人又感伤
It's so sweet and so sad.
他比我想象中有人情味多了
He's so much more sensitive than I ever thought.
他们的关系很特别 要是有天卢克写出
They had a special bond. I wouldn't be surprised
像《相约星期二》那样的书也不奇怪
if one day he wrote a book like "Tuesdays with Morrie".
那本书我倒没读过
I never read it.
不过主人公偷了莫里家的电视没
Did that guy steal Morrie's TV?
让我们踏上冒险旅程吧
Now setting a course for adventure!
我跟孩子们都有过超棒的回忆
I've had great experiences with all my kids.
不过 也许我稍稍冷落艾丽克斯了
But I... I might have fallen behind a bit with Alex.
完全是我的责任
My fault completely.
还冒险呢 这是要去把狗牌
Adventure? We are throwing dog tags
扔到已经饱受污染的海里
into an already polluted ocean
搞不好会噎死一只水獭呢
where they will probably choke an otter.
就80%是我的责任
80% my fault.
亲爱的 我们这是来了结一个人的遗愿
Honey, we're bringing closure to a man's life.
我们一会儿爬到能俯瞰大海的高处
We'll hike up to the scenic overlook,
据说沃特就在那儿向他的妻子求婚的
where apparently, Walt proposed to his wife,
等到光线柔和静谧时 说些悼词
wait for the light to be just right, say a few words,
分享一些回忆
share some memories.
听起来倒有些诗意
That's kind of poetic.
有些纳瓦伙族的味道
Kind of Navajo.
你终于也上道了
Now you're getting it.
我们会让他带着尊严走完这一生
We'll be sending him off with a level of dignity,
幸运的话 我们有天也将体会
that if we're lucky, someday we'll experience, too.
这叫做...
It's called--
这是什么啊 沃特的旧电视吗
Hey. What do you got there? Walt's old TV?
他说过他死后我可以挑一件他的东西
He said I could take one thing after he died.
要是两件就好了
I wish he would've said two things.
我还想要那个按键很大的电话
I would've taken that phone with the big buttons.
我相信你们一起看电视的时候
I bet you guys had some really good times
一定很开心 对吧
watching this thing, right?
那倒没有 我屋里刚好差个电视而已
No. I just wanted a tv in my room.
听着 卢克
You know, Luke,
也许有更好的方法来纪念沃特
there might be a nicer way to honor Walt's memory.
什么意思
What do you mean?
比如说 你们喜欢一起打理花园
Well, I mean, you guys liked to garden.
我们可以从他的花园挑一枝花
We could, uh, we could take one of his flowers
栽到咱家院子里 每当春天到来时
and plant it in our yard, and then every spring, when--
这样就好了
There we go.
亲爱的 你心里什么滋味
Sweetie, how are you feeling?
难过 还是生气
You sad? Angry?
困惑 还是沮丧
Confused? Frustrated?
你有什么想法都可以跟我说
You know you can talk to me.
知道啦 你挡着电视了 快闪开行吗
I know, but I can't see through you. Could you scootch?
不行 这样可不行
No. No. You know, this is not okay.
我要把它送回去
It's going back.
什么 他说我可以挑一件的
What? He said I could pick one thing.
这不叫挑
This isn't picking.
这叫抢 我要送回去了
It's looting, and it's going back.
你真是个坏女人
You are so mean.
那会儿沃特经常拿望远镜偷看你
When Walt used to look through those binoculars
还说什么"你爸真是好福气" 他错了
and say, "Your dad's one lucky man", he was wrong.
嗨 海莉
Hi, Haley.
嗨 斯蒂芬 山姆 这是曼尼
Hi. Stef, Sam, this is Manny.
你好啊 老兄
What's up, dude?
厨房在那边 泳池在后面
Kitchen's over there and pool's in the back.
你爸妈没来吗
So where are your parents?
他们不来
They're not coming.
我妈说会有监护人到场的啊
I was told there'd be a chaperone.
有啊 就是你
There is. It's you.
我爸妈觉得没问题
My parents are totally fine with it.
我想想 安全出口
Well, exits,
灭火器 烧伤药箱
fire extinguisher, burn kit.
都齐全 来找点乐子吧
Okay, let's have some fun.
我相信我说得很明白 禁入卧室
I believe I was clear the bedrooms were off-limits.
小姑娘 送你一句箴言
Young lady, I don't think you're ready up here
张腿先过脑 开窍不开苞
for what you're planning to do up there.
在我眼皮底下别想
Ugh. Not on my watch.
菜做得真美味啊 米奇尔
Oh, this was a delicious meal, Mitchell.
要是我老婆厨艺这么棒就好了
I wish my wife could cook a roast like this.
你是好福气啊 儿子
You got a good one there, son.
没错 我的福分 就像你跟妈妈一样
Oh, well, I'm very lucky, just like you and mama.
幸福美满一辈子
Never had a bad patch.
除了1985年冬天的那次 还记得吗
Except the winter of '85. Remember that?
那可不 那几晚我只好睡牛床上了
Oh, I spent several nights in the cow bed then.
来来来 我帮你收拾
Oh, here. Let me help you.
不用不用 你坐下
No, no, no. You sit--sit down.
我们男人们来叙叙旧
Let--lets us guys catch up here a little bit.
告诉你们我很烦那人的原因吧
I'll tell you why I don't like that guy--
我是不会跟米奇尔说的
and I could never say this to Mitch--
他把我儿子当做女人一样对待
He treats my son like the wife in the relationship.
一直都这样
Always has.
吃甜点前 我要送些礼物给你们
Before we get to dessert, I've got some presents here.
不用这么客气啦 老爸
Oh, you didn't need to, dad.
大爱啊
Love it!
哇 莫尔 真是太谢谢你了
Oh, Merle, thank you so much.
瞧瞧这个 真是典雅大方
Look at this. Oh. So elegant, huh?
真是太贴心了
Oh, this is so sweet.
感动得快哭出来了
I think I might cry.
千万别
Don't.
老爸 我真的要回家了
Dad, I really gotta get home.
我知道 我知道 你要做作业
I know. I know. You gotta do homework.
但是当你看到一个牌子上写着
But you can't expect me to see a sign that says,
"世间绝迹之美味奶昔 前50英里"
"World's greatest milk shake--50 miles,"
怎能不驱车前往呢
and not drive to it.
对不起两位 机器坏了
Sorry, sweetie. Machine's broken.
我就是想和我家闺女度过特别的一天
I just wanted a special day with my daughter,
比如"我们在海滩上给一位老人
You know, like "the time we gave an old man
办了场意义非凡的送别仪式"
a dramatic sendoff at the beach,"
或者"有次我们开了100英里
or--or "the time we drove 100 miles
去吃世界上最美味的奶昔"
for the world's greatest milk shake."
要生的时候给我们电话 弗朗辛
Call us when it happens, Francine.
你们到家前我说不定就要生了
Oh, it could be before you get home.
预产期已经过了一周了
I'm a week past my due date as it is.
要吃点什么吗
What can I do for you?
"有次我们帮忙接生了个孩子"
"The time we delivered a baby."
那儿除了她就是我们了 她又快生了
We were the only ones there, and she was so close,
一根针掉到地上的声音都能起到催生作用
The sound of a pin dropping could induce labor.
好
Okay!
吃什么好呢
What looks good?
孩子都爱搞破坏
Wh-whoa! Kids love to destroy things.
曼尼不这样 他一直都太一本正经了
Not Manny. He's always been a little bit too serious.
一般我负责造房子 他就负责来验收
I would make the buildings, and he would inspect them.
一旦哪里不合法规 各种批文就来了
And if they weren't up to code, ay, ay, ay, the paperwork.
我记得小卡有一次
I remember Cam, one time,
把拖拉机轮胎滚进了鸡窝
rolled a tractor tire right through a chicken coop.
他那时候才3岁
He was 3 at the time.
我记得米奇尔有一次
I remember Mitchell, one time,
空手劈向一块厚玻璃板
karate-chopped a plate glass window.
缝了17针
Got 17 stitches.
我爱死这个故事了
Ah, yes. I love that story.
他扮演的是霹雳娇娃[女]中的哪一个来着
Which one of the Charlie's angels he was being again?
-那不重要 -我觉得是费拉
- That's not important. - I think it was Farrah.
对 我记得米奇尔讲那个故事的时候
Yeah, the thing I remember is, when Mitchell told that story,
一直在咯咯笑
how--how he giggled all the way through.
我想他没有在咯咯笑
I'm sure he wasn't giggling.
他绝对在咯咯笑
Oh, yeah, he--he was giggling, all right.
不 米奇尔通常都是爆笑
No, see, Mitchell has a booming laugh.
卡梅隆才是那个喜欢尖声笑的
It's Cameron, actually-- has the high laugh.
像是
You know...
不 我觉得米奇的笑声更尖
No, I think Mitch has a higher laugh than--
是这样
It's...
不 是这样
No, it's...
听听他俩
Listen to them.
好哥俩啊这是
Best of friends.
亲爱的 我很抱歉我那么说杰
Oh, man. I'm sorry I doubted Jay.
他很贴心
He's been lovely.
好吧 真心话时间
Oh, well, confession time--
他确实有点不想来
He kinda didn't want to come.
听到这个你一定很想笑
Well, you're gonna laugh
因为我爸也有点希望他不要来
because my dad was kinda hoping he wouldn't.
什么
Wha?
他们只是需要多互相了解一下
Oh. They just needed to get to know one another better.
我真高兴我们做到了
I am so glad that we did this.
我也很高兴
Yeah, me, too.
说来有趣
Oh, that's so funny.
你爸为什么不喜欢我爸
Wh-what did your dad not like about my dad?
你知道杰的 他可爱得很
Oh, well, you know Jay. He's a teddy bear,
但有时候 他总以一副硬汉冷面孔示人
but sometimes he can kinda come off as a tough guy.
那倒是真的
Yeah, that's true.
作为一个真正的硬汉
As an actual tough guy,
你就能理解为什么我爸会被惹到了
You can kinda see how that would rub my dad the wrong way.
那个...我看得出来 不过
Oh, it's--I-I could see that, but, you know,
我爸其实真是个硬汉 所以...
my dad's actually pretty tough himself, so...
是吗 都市硬汉而已
Oh, yeah, city tough,
而不是 乡野硬汉
You know, not farm tough.
你说的都市 是指黑帮遍布的那种吧
You mean cities, where there are gangs,
乡野可就不一样了 遍布的都是小鸭子
as to opposed to farms, where there are ducks?
天呐 里面卡得死死的
Oh, boy. It's really jammed in there.
老爸 要不你过去搭把手吧
Yeah. Why don't you hop on in there, dad?
我爸能搞定
My dad's got it.
-好 我来看看 -坚持住 莫尔
- All right, let's see here. - Hang on, Merle.
-等等 这里吗 -撑住 好
- Wait. Here. Huh? - Hold. Yeah, that's good.
快出来了
Oh. It's coming.
我们能搞定 我们能搞定
We got it. We got it.
这就对了 这就对了
Oh, there you go. There you go.
小卡 帮我们拿点冰饮来吧
Cam, why don't you go get us a couple of cold ones?
这边交给我们就行了
We'll finish this job up in here.
当然 老爸 应该的
Sure thing, dad. You earned it.
对 谢谢帮忙 莫尔
Yeah. Good helping there, Merle. Okay.
这里面真热
It's hot in here.
有80华氏度吧[27摄氏度左右]
It's, like, 80 degrees.
他这么做是让外卖女郎
He did that so the meals on wheels lady
不得不宽衣解带
had to take off her sweater.
这儿灯是怎么开的
How do we turn on the lights in here?
可不是嘛
Of course.
卢克 既然我们到这儿了
So, Luke, now that we're here,
要不你就跟我说说沃特对你有多重要
you wanna take a minute and say what Walt meant to you?
不想说
Nope.
卢克 你正经历漫漫人生路上的重要一课
Luke, you are going through something huge in your life,
我担心你没能以一种
and I'm concerned that you're not processing it
恰当的方式去处理
in a normal, healthy way.
我伤心 我特别非常地伤心
I'm sad. I'm so very sad.
别 你别说这些来应付我
No, I don't just wanna hear what you think I wanna hear.
-我希望你敞开心扉... -你们好
- I want you to really tell me-- - Hi.
我是来来送餐的金姆
It's Kim with meals on wheels.
卢克 沃特在哪里
Hi, Luke. Where's Walt?
热得跟蒸桑拿一样 他怎么受得了
It is like a sauna in here. How does he stand it?
沃特 我在等我的每日一抱
Walt! I'm waiting for my hug!
关于沃特 我有个不幸的消息
I have some sad news about Walt.
他去世了
He's dead.
什么
What?
昨晚去世的
He died last night.
你在开玩笑吧
Are you joking?
不 他是心脏病去世的
No. He had a heart attack.
有人去世了 你却 你还笑得出来
A man died. You're-- you're smiling.
我没在笑
I'm not smiling.
撒谎 老妈 吓死个人哦
You are, mom. It's kinda creepy.
有人在吗 沃特
Well, hello? Walt?
发生什么了
What's going on?
沃特怎么了
Something happen to Walt?
我想你可以猜到的
Well, I'm sure you can imagine.
他病了吗
He sick?
他现在在医院吗
He's in the hospital?
天啊 没卖关子了
Oh, my god. Just tell me.
好吧
Mm! Okay.
他去世了
He is... dead.
-真的吗 -对 他去世了
- He is? - Yeah, he's dead.
你捂着个嘴做什么
What are you doing with your mouth?
-没什么 -她在笑 她觉得很滑稽
- Nothing. - She's smiling. She thinks it's funny.
我没有 我没觉得很滑稽
I don't. I don't think it's funny.
-我没在笑 -我不会把这个留给你的
- I'm not smiling. - I'm not leaving this with you.
抱歉 我很抱歉
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
我也才知道我脸有这毛病
I just found out my face does this.
老妈 你这样是大不敬啊
Wow, mom. That was so wrong.
这只是应对机制的不同 卢克
Well, it's--it's called a coping mechanism, Luke.
有些人会选择压抑自己的情感
Some people repress their feelings
有些人则会选择微笑 不说了越描越黑
and some people just smile. But d--it doesn't matter.
把电视机放回小屋去 赶紧离开这儿
Just put the TV in the den. Let's get out of here.
电视机不是放在小屋的
It doesn't go in the den.
应该放在这儿
It goes right here.
从我的房间就能看见它了
I can see it from my room.
有时候大半夜 我醒来时
Sometimes I'd wake up in the middle of the night
往这边一瞧
and look down here.
看电视机开着 就知道他还没睡
If the tv was on, I knew he was up,
我也说不清
and I don't know,
我想我会怀念这种感觉的
I guess I'm gonna miss that.
这真是...
Yeah. That's...
是啊
Yeah.
好点了吗
Is that any better?
还是有那么点儿 摇摇晃晃的
Yeah, it still feels just, you know, a little wobbly.
我的天 不不
Oh! Oh, my god. Okay, no, no, no.
没事 没关系 谢谢你 谢谢你
That's--that's fine. Thank you. Thank you.
好吧 看样子是时候了
Okay, it's "Go" Time.
好啊 医生
Oh, hey, doc.
没事的 阵痛而已
It's okay. It's just a cramp.
你们还要点些别的吗
Can I get you guys anything else?
可千万别 他已经让我吃遍
Please, no. He's already made me eat
菜单上"世间绝迹"的各种美食了
the world's greatest everything on the menu.
老爸 你今天怎么这么诡异
Dad, why are you acting like this?
是跟沃特去世有关吗
Is this about Walt dying?
不 与他在世时没来得及做的事有关
No. It's about what he didn't do when he was alive--
他没能和女儿共创特殊的美好回忆
Have a special bond with his daughter.
我不想成为他那样的一个父亲
I don't want to be that kind of dad.
要做就做尤金·塞尔南那样的
I want to be Eugene Cernan.
尤金·塞尔南是谁
Who's Eugene Cernan?
阿波罗17号的宇航员
"Apollo 17" Astronaut,
月上最后一人 史上最酷的爹
Last man on the moon, coolest dad of all time.
他离开月球时 他俯下身去
When he was leaving the moon, he reached down
把他女儿名字的缩写 刻在了月球表面
and wrote his daughter's initials into the lunar surface.
由于月球上没有空气流动
Since there's no atmosphere--
所以它会永远留在那
There'll be there forever.
所以每次当她仰望天空时
Wow. So every time she looks in the sky,
就能收到那专属于她的讯息
she knows there's a message just for her.
没错 全世界的爹都恨尤金·塞尔南
Exactly. That's why dads everywhere hate Eugene Cernan.
不是吧
Oh, no.
好吧 "恨"这字眼确实重了 只是
Okay, "Hate's" A strong word. It's just--
我是想说
I'm trying to make--
天啊
Oh. Oh, boy.
亲爱的
Honey. Okay.
我是真想帮你
I really wanna help,
不过都说见别人打哈欠或呕吐时
but you know when someone yawns,
自己也会有反应
It makes you yawn?
你也想吐了 是吗
You're not gonna yawn, are you?
都已经到嗓子眼了 天哪
I already yawned a little in my mouth. Oh, god.
杰 帮了这么大忙 真得谢谢你
Jay, I want to thank you for helping me do this.
小卡肯定很开心 不用自己一人忙活了
I know Cam appreciates not having to do it all on his own.
怎么 摆什么臭脸呢
What? What's that face?
你真想知道
You really wanna know?
当然
Sure.
有时候我觉得 在他们的关系中
Sometimes I think you treat my son
你把我儿子当成女人
like the woman in their relationship.
-什么 -比如那对表
- What? - Like those watches.
小卡那块又大又爷们
Cam's was all big and manly.
另一只看起来
The other one looked like something
就像是格蕾丝·凯莉的表
Grace Kelly would wear.
那是因为
Well, that's just because
米奇的手腕比小卡的要纤细 仅此而已
Mitch has a more slender wrist than cam does. That's all.
他那是瘦 不是纤细
It's skinny, not slender.
那你老老实实告诉我
And you're honestly telling me
你没把米奇放在类似女人的角色中
you don't cast mitch in the more ladylike role?
你是说小卡扮演的是老婆的角色吗
Are you saying Cam is the wife in this deal?
我没那么想过
I don't think about it that way.
现在可不像我们当年那样了
It's not like it was in our day.
出门养家糊口的是老公
Husband went out to work.
在家相夫教子的是老婆
Wife stayed home with the kids.
真会说话 拐弯抹角地说小卡是女人呗
That sounds like a clever way of saying "Yes."
好吧
Fine.
他们是平等的
They're both equal.
没有谁是女方
Neither one is the wife.
对 对
Yeah. Yeah.
我其实也很明白
I know that in my head.
只是当我觉得跟他相守一生的人
It's just that it makes me feel a tiny bit better
其实有那么一点像女人时
to think that the person he's spending his life with
我心里会好过些
is a tiny bit of a woman.
我懂的
I get it.
每次我对这事刚能接受一点时
Every time I start to feel comfortable with this thing,
就又会有新的事情发生让我烦心
some new part comes up I gotta wrap my head around.
事已至此 坦然接受吧
Yeah, I guess we got no choice.
对 我们都有两个儿子
Yep. We got two sons,
都为对方的基情所倾倒
and they're gay for each other.
回家路上我会慢点开的
I'll take it slow on the way home.
别担心 冒险旅程取消
Don't worry. Canceling course for adventure.
你猜什么将永存我心难以忘记
You know what I'll never forget?
就是我爸花了一整天
The time my dad spent the entire day
就为了要给我制造些特殊的回忆
trying to create a special memory for me.
还有 有个孕妇踩着我的呕吐物滑到了
Or when a pregnant lady slipped in my vomit.
等着
Hang on.
走之前我得做件事
I wanna do one thing before we go.
你在回家路上了吗
Hey, you on your way home?
快了 你那边怎么样了
Just about. How's everything there?
事实上 一切进展顺利
Actually, it's pretty great.
我等不及要见你了
I can't wait to see you.
我也是
Me, too.
好的
Okay.
走吧
Let's hit it.
要不然
I don't know.
回家路上我们买点吃的带回去吧
I feel like maybe we should get some food on the way home.
可别
Don't.
来个金枪鱼三明治
Maybe a nice tuna melt.
别说了
Stop it.
我已经尽力了妈妈 简直跟噩梦一样
I did what I could, mom. It was a nightmare.
我都不知道我关了多少次浴室的灯
I can't tell you how many times I turned off the bathroom light.
海莉
Haley!
糟了 听我说 歌洛莉亚
Oh, crap. Listen, Gloria.
我之前对你讲的 严格说不算是...
Okay, everything I told you technically was not--
你对我撒谎
You lied to me
就为了没人管 为所欲为地开派对
so that you could have a party without supervision!
今天晚上管事的还真不少
Oh, I had plenty of supervision.
他整晚都拿着杯垫和吸尘器跑来跑去
He was running around all night with his coasters and vacuum
义正言辞地教育别人要"做正确的决定"
and his "Make good choices" Speech.
很好 总得有个人有点责任心吧
Good. Somebody needed to be responsible.
谢谢
Thank you.
没说你 你太一本正经 太刻板了
Not you. You take rules too seriously.
倒成我错了
I'm in trouble?
你才13岁
You are 13.
你不应该在派对上用吸尘器打扫
You're not supposed to be vacuuming the party.
你应该享受这个派对才是
You're supposed to be enjoying the party.
就是嘛
Exactly.
而你压根不应该参加这样的派对
A party that you shouldn't have been having!
似乎你的逻辑有点混乱
It seems like you're sending mixed signals here.
也许我应该叫朋友们都走了
Yeah, maybe I should get my friends and just leave.
不 你麻烦大了 小姑娘
No, you're in trouble, little young lady.
这派对不能停
You're having this party!
什么 他们在泳池边用玻璃餐具
What? They've been using glassware by the pool,
把脚放在家具上
putting feet on the furniture,
还求女生互相亲对方
and begging girls to kiss each other.
对 这些事就是你应该干的
Yes! All the things that you should have been doing!
对 这些都没问题
Yeah, all those things are fine.
去吧 去好好玩 疯一疯
Go. Have fun and go crazy.
他会毁了我的派对的
But he's gonna ruin my party.
一石二鸟 一箭双雕
Two birds with one bullet.